Randy Faison

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with 5 years of background in Information Technology. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications. Known among staff for strong wit and attention to detail no matter the complexity of the project, recently earned a Certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University of Richmond.

Technical Skills

HTML, Git, CSS, CSS3, Javascript, Java, JQuery, Web-API's, Third party API's, Server Side API's, RESTful APIs, NODEJS, OOP, Express, MySQL, NoSQL, Oracle, ORM, MVC, REACT.js, Backend Development, Algorithm and Software Development, C++, Linux, Spring, Angular.

Projects

Note Taker: As a small business owner, I want to be able to write and save notes so that I can organize my thoughts and keep track of tasks I need to complete.

- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Express.
- GitHub: https://github.com/randyfasion/Note-Taker
- Deployed Application: https://randynotetaker.herokuapp.com

Team Profile Generator: This application takes in information about a team at a Software Engineering company. It then generates a HTML page to display all the information that was entered about the team. Also, all four of the class modules (employee, intern, manager, and engineer) are tested using Jest.

- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jest.
- GitHub: https://github.com/randyfasion/Team-Profile-Generator

Experience

CyberClean Systems; Richmond, VA. (December 2019 - current) Robotics Applications Engineer.

- Train essential personnel how to use Robotic software, increasing efficiency and output of products.
- Testing, evaluating, and modifying parts to ensure effectiveness.
- Providing technical advice for clients in order to ensure peak performance.

Cenveo Worldwide Limited; Richmond, VA. (September 2019 - December 2019) IT Analyst/Programmer

- Develop, document, analyze, create, test, and modify computer systems, programs, and integrations to improve customer satisfaction.
- Design efficient IT systems to meet business and customer needs, and debug programs by testing for and fixing errors to improve reliability.

LockLane Management, LLC. (May 2019 - August 2019) Intern-Web Development

• Assist in the design and implementation of websites through the use of Software Development practices to create a more user friendly experience.

Education

University of Richmond, Richmond, VA.

School of Professional and Continuing Studies.

Certificate: Full Stack Web Development.

Old Dominion University, Norfolk, VA.

Randy Faison

Major: Information Systems & Technology.

Bachelor of Science.